Hello everyone, in this video, we will introduce the new feature in the 2024 version of software model simulation.
The software model function will make the skin of the virtual model flexible.
When wearing tight clothing, the skin surface will be squeezed, just like human skin.
This function only works for Marvelous Designer VR default virtual model.
The function can also be used to automatically convert virtual models.
After preparing your MD virtual model or virtual model after conversion, we will learn how to use software model simulation.
Click on the virtual model, its properties will appear in the attribute editor window.
When you select the software model simulation, an option for adjusting the strength of the software model will appear at the bottom.
The smaller the strength of the software model, the softer the skin of the virtual model,
the more the skin is soft and the more the clothing is affected.
When selecting the software model simulation, a small icon will appear in the lower right corner of the 3D window,
reminding you that the software model simulation has been started.
When the simulation is started, you will see the skin sound bandage change.
You can't directly click and drag the virtual model skin to make it transform.
The software model needs to act on it through clothing.
When the software model simulation is started, the animation will be recorded.
The animation of the software model simulation will be recorded along with the clothing animation.
And the software simulation will record an animation layer independently.
The animation of the software model can only be exported through the Alembic file format.
If you export it in other 3D formats, it will only export the current model.
Now let's export the Alembic file.
When exporting the Alembic file, be sure to select the virtual model.